Ryan Allred

Software Developer

629-238-3243 ryanallred91@gmail.com www.github.com/Ryan-L-Allred https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-lee-allred/ https://ryanallred.netlify.app

PROFILE

I am an artist who has made the transition to software development. I am a determined and resilient life-long learner with the ability to laser focus and to accomplish professional and personal goals through diligent and thorough planning. I approach big problems by breaking them down in to smaller pieces, formulating creative solutions to each piece. Drawing from my experience in martial arts, I practice the utmost humility and dedication to constant never-ending improvement.

SKILLS

- · Technologies:
 - React.is
 - Javascript
 - C#
 - .NET
 - SOL
 - HTML
 - CSS
- Experienced with GitHub in a group and individual setting
- · Proficient with Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator
- Experienced with Autodesk Maya
- Problem Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Pattern Recognition
- Interpersonal Communications
- · Microsoft office
- Documentation Creation and Management

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp August 2022 - February 2023

Middle Tennessee State University

Bachelor of Science - Digital Animation August 2010 - May 2015

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Warranty Jewelry Services (WJS) at Asurion Sizing Technician

October 2017 - July 2022

Responsible for resizing white gold, yellow gold, and sterling silver rings that were sent in by the client, soldering rings back together, rounding and cleaning the inside of the rings, shaping and cleaning the outside of the rings, and the filling of cracks in the rings through the utilization of a laser welder.

Quality Land Management Spray and Lawn Care Technician

May 2016 - October 2017

Responsible for the handling, mixing, and application of herbicides, pesticides, and fertilizers for turfgrass and ornamentals, as well as operating heavy machinery including spray trucks carrying over 1,000 gallons of chemicals, zero turn lawn mowers, spraying apparatuses, and walk-behind lawnmowers.